在前一个视频里 我已经向你演示了当设置每个子元素的宽度为match_parent的时候
In a previous video, I showed you what happens when you set match parent for
会发生什么
the width of each of these child views.
TextView的宽度会扩展至父元素的宽度
The text view ends up extending across the full width of the parent.
这道题没有标准答案
There's no right or wrong solutions for how you experimented with the code.
这也可能是另一种你曾经的尝试
Here's another thing you could've tried.
如果你把线性布局改成水平
If you set the linear layout to have an orientation of horizontal,
所有的View就会在一个水平线上呈现
then the views will be displayed in a horizontal row.
如果你对Vip名单的宽度设置为match_parent
If you set match parent for the width of the VIP list,
很不巧 它就会把所有其他的View推出屏幕
then it unfortunately knocks off the other views off the screen.
如果你把高度设置为match_parent 你就会发现
If you set match parent for the height of the text you, then you see that
VIP列表的TextView会和其父元素一样高
the VIP list text view is now the full height of the parent linear layout.
同样地 这也可以适用于其他子元素的View
The same can be done for the other children views, or
或者你可以设定一个固定高度
you can set a fixed height.
在先前的视频里 我们向你展示了当设置子元素的宽度
In the previous video, we showed you what happens when you set matched parent
为match_parent时的境况
for the width of each of these child text views.
TextView和作为线性布局的父元素一样宽
The text view extends to the full width of the parent linear layout.
如果你为TextView设定一个固定的高度 如300dp
If you set a fixed height on the TextView, like 300 DP,
那么它在设备上就像这样
then this is what it will look like on the device.
没有标准答案 只要你试过就可以了
There's no right or wrong answers for what you tried out.